Hiroko Yamaji Software Engineer (React.js)

Setagaya, Tokyo Japan hiroko@hirokoymj.com www.hirokoymj.com 080-8452-9789

Skills

- React
- React Hooks
- Redux
- JavaScript (ES6)
- Lodash
- Node.js
- Apollo Server/Client
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Responsive Web Design
- Material UI
- Bootstrap 4
- Webpack 4
- Git
- GitLab

Software

- Visual Studio Code
- Heroku
- Photoshop CC
- Figma
- Slack/Google Meet

APIs

- Google Map
- OpenWeatherMap

Languages

- Japanese
- English

US Status

Green card holder

I am a Software Engineer who lived in Los Angeles for 16 years and moved back to Japan on November 2020 because of the COVID-19 pandemic. I am specialized in building a responsive web application using React.js. I currently live in Tokyo and am looking for Front-End engineer position.

FRONT-END (React): https://www.hirokoymj.com

BACK-END (GraphQL): https://hirokoymj-backend.herokuapp.com/ **CODE SAMPLE:** https://github.com/hirokoymj/hiroko-frontend

Work Experience (selected)

HyreCar Inc. (providing a driver and a car for Uber)
January 2019 – December 2020, Los Angeles, California, USA
Software Engineer (React/GraphQL)

- Developed HyreCar dashboard web application using React.js.
- Refactoring the dashboard app with React Hooks and Material UI.
- Collaborated other developers using Git and GitLab.

Beachbody.com (e-commerce company for a fitness)
December 2017 – September 2018, Santa Monica, California USA
Software Engineer (React)

Strategic Partners Inc. (creating a medical fabric such as scrubs)
December 2016 – June 2017, Chatsworth, California, USA
Software Engineer (React, Angular)

Teleflora.com (e-commerce company for a flower arrangement)
October 2009 – October 2016, Los Angeles, California, USA
Front End Web Developer

MC Squared (Advertisement-agency that is specialized in a real estate.) September 2006 – November 2007, Los Angeles, California USA **Web Developer (PHP)**

Sony Electronics Inc. (Contractor)
July 2005 – July 2006, Santa Monica, California USA
Web Developer (Java)

Techfirm, Inc. (software development firm)
December 1998 – December 2002, Tokyo, Japan
Software Engineer (Java)

Education

Santa Monica College - Certificate of Interactive Media February 2004 - June 2005, Santa Monica, California, USA

Yamawaki Gakuten Junior College - AA of Food Science April 1989 – March 1991, Tokyo, Japan